Register of the Myers G. Lowman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1920-1964 (Boxes 1-85)
  - Weinstone, William
  - Weisman, Steve
  - Wells, Garveth
  - Weniger, Guy Archer
  - West, George P. (Box 82)
  - Westinghouse Corporation
  - White, Walter
  - White, William Allen
  - Whitney, Charlotte A.
  - Williams, Aubrey
  - Williams, Claude C.
  - Williams Brothers
  - Williams, Howard Y.
  - Wirin, Abraham
  - Winchell, Walter
  - Wine, James W.
  - Wirt, William
  - Wolfe, Henry C.
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
  - Wooley, Mary
  - World Council of Churches
  - World Federalism
  - World Peace, Board of (Methodist Church)
  - Wyker, James D.
  - Yard, Molly (Box 83)
  - Yarmolinsky, Adam
  - YMCA
  - Young, Kimball
  - Young, Stephen
  - Young Communist League
  - Young Pioneers
  - Young Workers' Communist League
  - Youth
  - Youth Against War and Fascism (YAWF)
  - Youth Committee Against War
  - Youth Congress (Box 84)
    - American and national
    - 1940
    - World
  - Youth hostels (Box 85)
  - YWCA
  - Zellner, James
  - Zeuch, William E.
  - Zioncheck, Marion
- Printed Matter (Boxes 86-91, 94-95)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings, reprints, bulletins, leaflets, and other printed matter on various political subjects (Boxes 86-91)
  - Unarranged material, primarily printed matter, relating to communism and civil rights in southern states (Boxes 94-95)
- CLOSED (Boxes 92-93)
- Sound Recordings, 1960-1969 (Boxes 96-100)
  Sound tape reels. Titles taken from box labels.
  - Air Institute - WMNI News - 920 Radio (tapes 1 and 2), undated
  - "Catholicism," M. G. Lowman, Radio WMOV, Mobile, 4-4:30 pm, undated
  - Citizens' Council Forum
    - Program number 6008, undated
    - Program number 6231, undated
    - Program number 6235R (2 copies), undated
    - Program number 6244R, undated
    - Program number 6329, appearance by Rep John Bell Williams and M. G. Lowman, undated
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 67019_a_0000210_a01
    - Program number 6330, undated
    - Program number 6331, undated
    - Program number 6332, undated
    - Program number 6425R (2 copies), undated
    - Program number 6426R, undated
    - Program number 6427R, undated
      Use copy reference number: 67019_a_0000212_a01
      Includes an appearance by M. G. Lowman.
    - Program number 6429R, undated
    - Program number 6430, undated
    - Program number 6546, undated
      Use copy reference number: 67019_a_0000211_a01
      Possibly program number 6546R with an appearance by M. G. Lowman.
    - Program number 6547R, with Joseph Dumbacher, undated
    - Program number 6548R, Joseph Dumbacher - "Infiltrated SDS" (2 copies), undated
      Use copy reference number: 67019_a_0000209_a01
    - Program number 6603R, undated
    - Program number 6604R, undated
      Use copy reference number: 67019_a_0000213_a01
  - Citizens' Council Forum, Number 3, M. G. Lowman, "National Council of Churches and Its Neon Sign" and "Cross Coat Lapel Christians,", undated
    An exposé concerning participants of street demonstrations and marches.
  - FBI, Portland, Oregon, undated
  - Highlander Folk School - Alleged communist involvement - Martin Luther King and Abner W. Berry (a member of National Committee of Communist Party): "Expand Race Revolution into the Violent Revolution" - N.A.A.C.P. fight for control, undated
  - Le Roi Jones, undated
  - Mobile, Alabama - M. G. Lowman, undated
  - "Paul Revere and Nine Men Against America," Buckner Fanning, undated
  - WRBE - M. G. Lowman, undated
  - WSLI, undated
  - WTUF - Mobile, Alabama, Mark Murray and M. G. Lowman, undated
  - WSOL, Tampa, Florida, programs number 1 and 2, "Dread of Life,", 1960 May 19
  - Interview on Citizens' Council Forum, M. G. Lowman, 1962 September 10
  - WTUF - M. G. Lowman, 1964 April 29
  - Mrs. H. A. Alexander, Mobile, Alabama, 1964 April 30
  - M. G. Lowman, Mobile, Alabama, 1964 May 1
    3 copies
  - M. G. Lowman, Mobile, Alabama, 1965 March 7
  - "Appeal to Negroes and Whites to Solve Their Problems Without Communists," M. G. Lowman, 1965 June 25
  - WONA - Winona, Mississippi, Mrs. Alexander and Joseph Dumbacher, 1965 November 6
  - Town Hall, Senotobia, Mississippi, 1965 November 8
  - M. G. Lowman and Joseph Dumbacher at Atlanta, 1965 November 17
  - Luncheon club - preparatory to election campaign. Dothan, Alabama, 1966 January 26
  - WMOO - Mobile, Alabama, M. G. Lowman, 1966
    - 1966 February 5 and 12
    - 1966 February 27
    - 1966 March 6
    - Martin Luther King, 1966 March 13
    - 1966 March 20
    - "Deception in the Churches,", 1966 March 27
    - 1966 April 3-4
    - "They Have Swept Away My Lord," Easter Sunday, 1966 April 10
    - 1966 April 17
    - 1966 April 24
    - "Catholic Dilemma,", 1966 May 1
    - "They Have Taken Away My Lord,", 1966 May 8
    - 1966 May 15
    - "The Church in Politics,", 1966 May 22
    - 1966 June 5
    - "Zellner and Bishop Goodson,", 1966 June 5
    - 1964 June 10
    - 1966 June 26
    - SCEF, Inc. Bishop Goodson, 1966 June 27
    - "Delta Ministry of National Council of Churches,", 1966 July 3
    - 1966 July 10
  - Greenville - Leland investigation of Delta Ministry, 1966 April 21
  - Citizens' Council Forum - 3 programs, M. G. Lowman, 1966 June 3
  - M. G. Lowman, 1966 June 19
  - M. G. Lowman, 1966 June 26
  - Jerry Rubin - Eden Park, 1969 April 20
- Motion Picture Film, 1957-1960 (Film shelf)
  - Four-day workshop (Labor Day) at Highlander Folk School, 1957 August 30 - September 2
    Important coup against race exploitation by Communist Party apparatus. Direct infiltration under M. G. Lowman's arrangement.
    Related Material at Other Institutions
    Ed Friend's Highlander Folk School film, Ed Friend visual materials, 1918-1990, Richard B. Russell Library for Political Research and Studies, University of Georgia, Athens, as presented in the Digital Library of Georgia.
  - San Francisco City Hall riots against House Committee on Un-American Activities, 1960
    Composite film made by newsmen and from other pictures of riots.
  - Videotape interview of Ku King Chang, one of the most important Taiwan Chinese anti-communists, undated
    M. G. Lowman's guest at Independence Hall, Knotts Berry Farm. Shows concern of Taipei in regard to the recent China policy of Nixon.
- Photographs, 1930-1968 (Photo file)
  - Communist demonstrations in U.S. cities (6 prints), 1930 (Envelope mA)
  - Meeting of civil rights activists, Highlander Folk School, Knoxville, Tennessee, 1957 (Envelope B)
  - Demonstration during voter registration drive, Greenwood, Mississippi, 1964 (Envelope C)
  - Demonstration during voter registration drive, Hattiesburg, Mississippi, 1964 (Envelope D)
  - Civil rights demonstrations, Jackson, Mississippi, 1964-1965 (Envelope E-F)
  - Civil rights workers, Camp Beulah, Mississippi (3 prints), 1965 (Envelope G)
  - Civil rights demonstration, Greenville, Mississippi, 1965 (Envelope H)
  - Anti-Vietnam War demonstration at the Federal Building, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1965 (Envelope I)
  - Participants at New Politics Meeting, Chicago, 1967 (Envelope J)
  - Poor People's March on Washington, D.C., 1968 (Envelope K)